<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events | Formal Methods Teaching Committee</title>
    <link>/categories/events/</link>
      <atom:link href="/categories/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Events</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 12:05:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hub96a365879c5829aace43d4a4da98a91_104111_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>/categories/events/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>FMTea 2019: Formal Methods Teaching Workshop and Tutorial</title>
      <link>/2019/10/03/fmtea-2019-formal-methods-teaching-workshop-and-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 12:05:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/2019/10/03/fmtea-2019-formal-methods-teaching-workshop-and-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FMTea 2019 Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://fmtea.github.io&#34;&gt;https://fmtea.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formal Methods provide software engineering with tools and techniques for
rigorously reasoning about the correctness of systems. While in recent years
formal methods are increasingly being used in industry, university curricula
are not adapting at the same pace. Some existing formal methods classes
interest and challenge students, whereas others fail to ignite student
motivation. We need to find ways to teach formal methods to the next
generation, and doing so will require us to adapt our teaching to the 21st
century students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FMTea19 is a combined workshop and tutorial at the 3rd World Congress on Formal
Methods, FM2019. Its aim is to share experiences of teaching formal methods
that have gone well, or that failed in surprising ways, as well as to develop
ways to reboot the presence of formal methods in curricula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tutorial-part-of-fmtea19&#34;&gt;Tutorial part of FMTea19&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are very pleased to have Carroll Morgan giving an invited talk on his
approach to and experiences with teaching formal methods to undergraduate
students. Sir Tony Hoare will also join us to give a talk on the foundations of
teaching computer science for future formal methods scientists. We will run two
more tutorial presentations, held by Holger Hermanns and Bas Luttik, on
experiences with concurrency and online teaching. Our goal is to discuss
various models of existing FM teaching, together with innovative proposals for
remaining relevant as educators of Formal Methods in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;workshop-part-of-fmtea19&#34;&gt;Workshop Part of FMTea19&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the workshop part of the event, we aim to attract papers detailing authors’
experiences with FM Teaching. We would like to get papers discussing successes
and failures of various methods, case studies, tools, etc. As self-learning
seems to be an important aspect of FM teaching, we appreciate experiences with
online teaching, including experiences with teaching formal methods via MOOCs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
