<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspiration | Formal Methods Teaching Committee</title>
    <link>/categories/inspiration/</link>
      <atom:link href="/categories/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Inspiration</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 12:05:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hub96a365879c5829aace43d4a4da98a91_104111_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Inspiration</title>
      <link>/categories/inspiration/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>(In-)Formal Methods: The Lost Art --- A Users’ Manual</title>
      <link>/2019/10/03/in-formal-methods-the-lost-art-a-users-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 12:05:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/2019/10/03/in-formal-methods-the-lost-art-a-users-manual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link to article:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;Morgan2016_Chapter_In-FormalMethodsTheLostArt.pdf&#34;&gt;InformalMethods-Morgan.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article describes an experimental course in &amp;ldquo;(In-)Formal
Methods&amp;rdquo;, taught for three years at the University of New South
Wales to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cse.unsw.edu.au/~cs6721/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;fourth-year undergraduate Computer-Science students&lt;/a&gt;. An adapted version was then taught
(disguised as “Software Engineering”) to &lt;a href=&#34;http://webapps.cse.unsw.edu.au/webcms2/course/index.php?cid=2332&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;second year undergraduate students&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourth-year CS students at UNSW are typically very-good-to-excellent
programmers. Second-year students are on their way to the
same standard: but many of them have not yet realised how hard it will
be actually to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, whether good or on the way to good, few of these students
have even heard of static reasoning, assertions, invariants, variants, let
alone have learned how to use them. . . None of the simple, yet profoundly
important intellectual programming tools first identified and brought to
prominence (more than 40 years ago) has become part of their program-
ming toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did this happen? How can it be changed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will happen if we do change it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below we address some of those questions, using as examples actual
material from the two related courses mentioned above; they were given
in the years 2010–4. As an appendix, we present feedback from some of
the students who took one course or the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, some suggestions are made about whether, when
and how courses like this one could possibly be taught elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secret Ninja Formal Methods</title>
      <link>/2019/10/03/secret-ninja-formal-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 12:05:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/2019/10/03/secret-ninja-formal-methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link to article:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;SecretNinjaFormalMethods-Kiniry.pdf&#34;&gt;SecretNinjaFormalMethods-Kiniry.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of formal methods can significantly improve software
quality. However, many instructors and students consider formal meth-
ods to be too difficult, impractical, and esoteric for use in undergraduate
classes. This paper describes a method, used successfully at several uni-
versities, that combines ninja stealth with the latest advances in formal
methods tools and technologies to integrate applied formal methods into
software engineering courses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
